- [Voiceover] ♫ In the
not-too-distant future,
♫ Next Sunday, A.D.,
♫ There was a guy named Joel,
♫ Not too different than you or me,
♫ He worked at Gizmonic Institute,
♫ Just another face in a red jumpsuit,
♫ He did a good job cleaning up the place,
♫ But his bosses didn't like him,
♫ So they shot him into space.
♫ We'll send him cheesy movies,
♫ The worst we can find, la la la,
♫ He'll have to sit and watch them all,
♫ And we'll monitor his mind, la la la,
♫ Now keep in mind Joel can't control,
♫ Where the movies begin or end, la la la,
♫ Because he used those special parts,
♫ To make his robot friends,
♫ Robot Roll Call, alright let's go,
♫ Cambot,
- [Cambot] Pan left.
♫ Gypsy
- [Gypsy] Hi, girl.
♫ Tom Servo,
- [Tom Servo] What a cool guy.
♫ Croooow,
- [Crow] He's a wise cracker.
♫ If you're wondering
how he eats and breathes,
♫ And other science facts, la la la,
♫ Then repeat to yourself,
"It's just a show,
♫ I should really just relax,
♫ For Mystery Science Theater 3000" ♫
(door shutting)
(banging)
- As the noose was fitted,
and as a delicate black mask
was tied around the prisoners eyes,
may the Lord have mercy on his
- Boring, boring!
- Hi everybody, welcome
to the satellite of Love,
I'm Joel Robinson and I'm with my robots,
Tom Servo and Crow T. Robot,
and I'm reading them some
really scary bedtime stories,
but they're so jaded, I mean,
kids today have seen and
heard everything, believe me.
- [Voiceover] Oh isn't that the truth?
Commercial sign in 30 seconds.
- Come on Joel, you've been reading us
nothing but the light stuff,
In Cold Blood, Helter Skelter,
the 17 novels that Stephen King
published this year, come on
read us something really scary.
- OK, I've been saving a really,
really, really scary one,
that is, if you guys
think you're old enough,
if you think you can handle it.
- Oh I'm sure it's really scary,
do I dare ask what it's called?
- Life's Little Instruction Book.
(laughing and mock horror)
Number one, put a lot of
marshmallows in your hot chocolate.
Number two, surprise a new neighbor
with one of your favorite homemade dishes,
and include the recipe.
Number three, at the
movies, buy Junior Mints
and sprinkle them on your popcorn.
Number four, enjoy real maple syrup.
- The humor, the humor.
(upbeat dance music)
Number 187, measure people
by the size of their hearts,
not by the size of their bank accounts.
- Oh that's enough, Joel,
I can't take anymore!
- Oh no, keep going.
- What are you crazy?
- [Tom] No, come on, shhh.
Number 188, when facing a difficult task,
act as though it's impossible to fail,
when going after Moby Dick,
take along the tartar sauce.
- Take along the tartar sauce!
(laughing)
- Hold the phone you two,
Mama and Peepop are calling.
- That's nothing Joel, Clive Barker says,
"I've seen the future of horror and
it's everything I need to know
I learned in kindergarten.
(laughing)
- Ready with the invention
exchange, Cheiferino.
- Each day Frank and I are faced
with many time constraints,
what with the mountain
of paper here at the lab,
Frank's social calendar,
and my Jazzercise,
we just don't have time to relax.
At the odd occasion we do have
an evening free to take in,
say a film, we run
around here like ninees,
trying to shower and shave and get there,
only to spend a half hour in line.
- So do what I do,
don't get ready to go
until you're already there.
How?
It's easy, with the new
Frank Brand Quick Primp Kit.
- That's right, spend the down time
doing something productive
like teasing your brow,
or finding your natural part.
Say for demonstration purposes
Frank and I are in line
to see, Out on a Limb.
- Well in that case
we'd be seated already.
- Frank.
- Okay, just for arguments sake,
lets say we're on line
to see, Out on a Limb.
Anyway, now I'm not nearly ready to go,
but it doesn't matter, I
merely take out this light
and portable Frank Brand
full length mirror,
then I quickly secure the
whisper weight Frank Brand
toiletry chapeau, really kind
of depends on the good graces
of the person standing in front of you.
I find average height really works best.
I'll be done in just a...
Do I look fat to you?
I'll be done in just a second.
(chuckling)
Back up to you Mr. R.
- Well our invention
exchange this week, Sirs,
takes us into the world of art.
- Abstract expressionism, it's what's hot.
All the kids are dying for it.
- That's why we've invented the
paint by number Mark Rathgo.
Now even little Johnny can
join the color field painters
and challenge the
convention of the art world.
- Yeah, let's see here, we've
got our number five paint,
it says number five here,
so we just dip the brush
and start paintin'.
It's fun.
- [Crow] Joel are you sure,
- [Crow] You're doin' that right?
Look at the box, hey?
Well what do ya know?
- What do you think, Sirs?
- I don't know much about
art, but I know what I like.
I like today's film you young
turks are in for the wackiest
ride since Richard Pryor
boarded the Silver Street.
Please enjoy, The Rebel Set,
but first, an apply named film
entitled, Johnny at the Fair.
(crashing)
- You mean like that?
- [Tom] No, lower.
- [Crow] Right in the center.
- [Tom] No, down.
(beeping)
- Oh, we've got movies starting.
(crashing)
- [Joel] Come on you
guys, now this is a short,
I don't want it getting too dark.
- [Crow] Okay, okay.
- [Joel] I know, it's a new
band from Seattle, right?
- [Tom] I'm gonna get Joe Louis.
- [Crow] Barbara Ann Scott,
the white bomber, I suppose?
- [Tom] Olsen and Johnson,
keeps baby's soft.
- [Joel] And Johnny, the
wonder something or other.
- [Tom] Oh look, it's
the Arc de Full Retreat.
- [Crow] Prozac at work
in today's society.
- [Voiceover] This is the story of Johnny.
- [Joel] A sad story.
- [Voiceover] It all happened
the day Johnny, his mother,
and his dad crossed the
border to see the famous
Canadian National Exhibition.
- [Tom] Oh that sounds great.
- [Voiceover] It was Johnny's
first real grown up trip
and there were many things to see.
- [Crow] This is the last
you'll see Johnny happy.
- [Voiceover] There were
exhibits on radio, electricity,
flowers, photography;
a real land of wonders.
- [Crow] Boring!
- [Tom] Boring!
- [Voiceover] And a whole Scottish band.
Johnny even got to the midway for a ride,
but the fun didn't last
nearly long enough.
- [Tom] Johnny's car rolled and burned.
- [Voiceover] There were
displays all over the world,
from countries Johnny
was just learning about.
Fine porcelains from France,
riches from the Orient,
silks and pearls from India...
- [Crow] Simulated
culture, like Disneyworld.
- [Voiceover] It had been a busy morning,
but Johnny's adventure really
began just before lunchtime.
- [Tom] A shot rang out!
- [Voiceover] Everyone
was having a good time,
but it's hard to decide where to go next.
- [Crow] How 'bout home?
- [Voiceover] "Let's go back
to the midway," he says,
pointing in the wrong direction.
"What Johnny?
No Johnny," says mom, "we're
going to the art gallery."
- [Tom] And you'll like it!
- [Crow] No, I don't wanna go!
- [Voiceover] Let's see what
Johnny can find for himself.
- [Joel] Johnny's negligent
parents let him wonder off.
- [Tom] Haight/Ashbury, please.
- [Voiceover] Johnny's
parents still can't decide.
At first they don't miss him.
- [Joel] Who would?
A feeling of elation.
- [Voiceover] Where's Johnny?
Where did that boy go.
With 250,000 people here,
how will we ever find him?
- [Joel] Johnny's parents
decide to move on,
and start their lives a new.
- [Crow] Ah, sweet freedom.
- [Tom] Everyone's galkin' at me.
- [Voiceover] Johnny puts
his best foot forward.
He isn't sure where he's
goin' but he's on his way.
- [Tom] Girls!
- [Crow] Run, boy, run!
(vocals of fireworks)
- [Voiceover] A baseball game, oh boy!
But when he gets there he finds
a five year old can't get
close enough to see anything.
- [Joel] Aside the Mariner's
are playing, so who cares?
- [Voiceover] Unless
someone lifts you up and
puts you on the lap of the
undefeated champion of
the world, Joe Lewis.
- [Crow] Joe hits Johnny up for 15 cents
due to tax problems.
- [Tom] Half the pain of
having feet is red goose shoes.
- [Voiceover] Next up, the horse show.
Johnny loves horses.
He's just in time,
for the judges are about
to award the prize.
- [Tom] And it goes to Johnny!
- [Voiceover] The winner
is this white beauty.
- [Crow] Oh my ear!!
Jeez, the horse from Equus
had it better than this.
- [Tom] Then Johnny trans
modifies, he's a shape-shifter,
and he breaks the fourth seal.
- [Voiceover] A five day old Shetland,
and was born right at the fair.
He weighs all of 24 pounds and
is just under two feet tall.
- [Joel] His parents didn't
abandon him, like Johnny's.
- [Crow] Whoops, sorry, Dad.
- [Tom] Johnny feels stock
hands pressing him onward.
The voices in his head get meaner.
- [Voiceover] Johnny can't read the words,
Chemical Wonderland,
- [Joel] We've all been there.
But there are lots of people in there,
so he thinks he'll check on things.
- [Crow] A whiskery man
hands him a small package,
"the first one's free," he says!
- [Voiceover] And a little
of that, and low and behold,
before his very eyes,
- [Crow] LSD.
A rubber ball!
(groaning)
Thank you.
- [Tom] Johnny must have
everything for himself.
- [Voiceover] Johnny's
off for more adventure.
Jee whiz, I'll bet they
don't have anything like this
in the art gallery.
- [Crow] Johnny distracts
the tightrope walkers
and they fall to certain doom.
- [Voiceover] And on bicycles, too.
- [Joel] Boy, they're sure tough
on drunk drivers in Canada.
(whistling)
- [Voiceover] Johnny is invited
to help put on the show,
and don't thin he doesn't enjoy himself.
- [Joel] That's a guy!
- [Voiceover] The only
problem is afterwards,
Johnny can't stop going up and down.
- [Crow] The drugs from
the Chemical Wonderland
start to kick in.
(laughing)
- [Voiceover] Johnny's mother
is still trying to find her
missing son and thinks she
might see Johnny on the edge
of the crowd gathered to hear the former
Prime Minister of Canada,
- [Joel] Yeah, right.
Mr. McKenzie King.
She never dreams her
Johnny is on the platform
discussing the situation
with the guest speaker.
- [Joel] Tell me Johnny,
now what do you think
of the new free trade agreement?
- [Tom] I have to go, horsies.
- [Crow] The hell was his name again?
Jimmy, no, Jerry...
- [Voiceover] Johnny gets an
escort down from the platform
and is off again.
- [Crow] It will be the
first of many encounters with
bouncers for Johnny.
(honking)
- [Voiceover] Oh boy,
a helicopter airplane.
- [Joel] What?
Jimminy, thinks Johnny,
if only I can get a ride in one of those.
- [Tom] Visions of the Mekong Delta
flash before Johnny's eyes.
- [Voiceover] What a day,
you never know who a fella will meet
when he's looking for a helicopter,
it's Barbara Ann Scott, the
World Champion Figure Skater.
- [Joel] She's the Cher of her time.
- [Crow] Jimminy, thinks Johnny,
if only I could get a
ride in one of those!
- [Voiceover] Johnny does
find a real airplane,
and gets his ride.
- [Joel] Johnny thinks Amelia Earhart
seems like a nice lady.
- [Voiceover] They take
a spin on Lake Ontario
to watch the start of the
international speedboat race.
- [Joel] Whoa, Johnny realizes
he's in over his head.
- [Crow] Johnny is irresponsibly
put into a dangerous
speedboat without a life jacket.
- [Joel] For the first
time in his young life,
Johnny knows real fear.
(screaming)
Johnny's hydroplane
disintegrates on impact.
- [Crow] Johnny's spirit
is completely broken.
- [Voiceover] By now the
spring in Johnny's step
is nearly gone, no lunch either.
- [Joel] ♫ Way for sail,
he's going cheap. ♫
- [Voiceover] Prime Ministers
are fine once in a while,
but there's just so much a guy can take.
- [Joel] Johnny realizes
what a lie his life has been.
- [Voiceover] Right now,
Johnny wants his mother.
Perhaps Olsen and Johnson,
the Hellzapoppin' boys,
can help cheer Johnny up.
- [Crow] Yeah, but if
you've seen their act
you know that's not likely.
- [Voiceover] Johnny wants no part though.
- [Joel] Johnny's got taste.
- [Voiceover] But there's
tricks to every trade
and the Hellzapoppin' Boys are tough,
even a very tired and hungry
Johnny is able to laugh.
- [Tom] Laugh, laugh, it's funny, laugh!
- [Voiceover] Finally, a
friendly policeman takes Johnny
to a building he hadn't planned on seeing.
- [Tom] Let me out!
Attica, Attica!
- [Voiceover] There
are 350 acres of ground
in Exhibition Park and
Mom and Pop have covered
every single acre looking for Johnny.
- [Joel] Did I tell you to have this baby?
- [Voiceover] They've looked everywhere.
Everywhere but one place.
- [Crow] Their own hearts.
- [Voiceover] He's about so high.
- [Joel] Well yes, there
was a Mr. Barty here.
(cheering and whistling)
- [Tom] Mommy had a little
vacation while you were lost.
- [Joel] Yeah right,
play it up big in public.
That's right.
- [Tom] And I met Joe Lewis,
and the Prime Minister, and...
- [Voiceover] Johnny fell
asleep on his father's shoulder.
He had managed to stay awake
just long enough to see the
beginning of the fireworks.
- [Joel] At home.
- [Crow] Johnny's
parents blamed each other
and never trusted again.
Good night.
- [Voiceover] Pleasant dreams, Johnny.
- [Joel] So long, sucker.
- [Crow] And let this
be a warning, to you!
(upbeat dance music)
(base instrument music)
Hey, there's a mingus among us.
- [Tom] You know, I got the
nicest rebel set for my wedding.
It's so nice.
- [Crow] Didja?
Oh yeah, it's a reasonable.
- [Crow] ♫ You say
petite, I'll say petite,
♫ Let's call the whole thing off. ♫
- [Joel] Man, I wish I could
afford a trap set, man.
Man.
- [Crow] Oh I never go
down to the village,
they're too nutty down there.
- [Crow] Oh yeah,
- [Tom] For sure.
they're crazy.
- [Joel] Looking very relaxed,
Adolf Hitler on vibes.
(beatnik music)
- [Tom] Cigar, cigarettes,
camu, startch, aunts,
alienation, vikenstein, ohhh
- [Joel] That was close.
(scatting)
Hey, it's Fisher and Statsky.
- [Crow] ♫ One night in Bangkok
makes a strong man crumble ♫
- [Joel] Boy those rebels really
go through the Swiss Miss.
- [Tom] You know, this is
the hippest Red Lobster
I've been to.
- [Joel] Watch it, here she comes again.
(sighing)
(scatting)
Waitress, 'scuse me, can we get some...
Oh forget it.
(scatting)
- For perfumes and prats
upon this beat still
(Crow's fake snores drown out speaker)
Through oceans and oceans
and legal commotion,
good cologne on the beards of each man.
- [Crow] Oh that's profound.
Check please!
- Oh King.
- Hey!
- [Joel] What do you want,
I'm a character actor.
- Good evening, Mr. T.
- [Tom] Hi Mr. B.
- Please, Sidney, it's Johnson's move.
- [Crow] They're having a
goatee staring contest, well?
- [Tom] Let's talk, we never talk.
- I'll have to take your Queen.
- [Crow] Sorry about that chief.
- Check, and mate.
- [Joel] Hey, you knocked my block off.
- You win Mr. Tucker.
- [Joel] Mr. Drunker?
- 12 minutes.
Perhaps you'll have better luck next time.
- [Crow] Let's play Chutes
and Ladders next time.
- [Joel] Milk money.
- Don't you ever lose one of those sets?
- Rarely, if ever.
- [Joel] Thanks for asking...
- Then you must be a
virtuoso, as they say.
- Yes and no, I merely make
sure that my antagonists
are bad chess players.
- [Joel] You're hard to talk to.
- Well watches, that comes
to an interesting $325.
- Oh, good hunting.
- [Crow] Boss, why are
you in your pajamas?
- For the waitress you pinched, Sidney.
- Oh Mr. T, what that's
how I express myself.
- [Joel] Express this.
- That might be quite true,
but this one is new here,
I haven't pinched her myself yet.
(booing)
- I'm just sayin' Mr. T., good hunting.
- Sidney, are you beat?
- Oh sure man, cool, way
out and long gone, Daddy.
- [Joel] Being sarcastic.
- It just takes that you
want things, and it shows.
- You want things yourself, Mr. T.;
money, things, and eccetera.
You own this joint and you work at it.
You even spotted them up.
- [Joel] Don't ever say that.
- When in Rome, Sidney, do the Romans.
Get these three gentlemen here
tonight after closing time.
- Then we're ready to move?
- We are indeed.
- [Joel] Tell 'em to bring boxes.
- George Lelund, you kiddin'?
- I never kid.
- Lelund's nothin' but a wild, young punk.
- [Crow] He's my wild, young punk.
- He's also the best rifle shot I know.
I believe it's the only thing
military school taught him.
- [Joel] His name's Oswald.
- Ray Miller?
John Mapes, that ham roller?
- [Joel] Come on, they're my friends.
- Si, Sidney, that ham roller.
- [Crow] We have nothing
to fear, but fear itself.
I can't help it, I'm the Fonz, yeah?
- [Tom] I hate character actors.
- [John] I am a gentleman.
- [Voiceover] That I'll try.
- [Crow] Oh great, another
oily, unlikable character.
- If you strike me again!
- [Voiceover] So you may lose your arm.
If you strike me you are
no gentleman,
- [Joel] It's Miss Hathaway!
And if no gentleman, why then no arm.
- A herald cape, oh put me in thy books.
What is your crest?
A cockstone,
- [Man] Henry Miller.
A cocktsone, a cockstone, a cockstone.
- [Joel] Now wait a minute,
it's a little late for acting lessons,
they started filming already.
- You're home kinda little late, Jeanne
- [Crow] Yes Master.
- Last minute rush
at the drive-in.
One of the girls didn't show up.
- [Crow] So, and?
She's dressed like Jack Lalanne.
- What difference does it make anyway?
- I just hate to see you
working so hard is all.
- [Joel] Then get a job.
- Then look the other way.
- [Joel] Ouch.
Murray, use a coaster.
- You know, I can do
without cracks like that.
- I'm sorry.
- I know it's rough on you honey,
but once I get a break
- [Joel] A new shirt...
- Johnny, how much longer we
gonna wait for that break?
- Well it could happen any day.
- Well it hasn't happened for
the last year and a half now.
(screaming in shock)
- I'm an actor, I've gotta be seen around.
- Where, in that beat coffee house?
- What do you expect me to do?
Make a fast 70, 80 bucks a week?
- That 70, 80 a week, faster
than you're making now.
- [Joel] Oh that hurts.
- You used to have faith in me.
- [Crow] Did I, when?
- I used to have faith in
lots of things, Johnny.
Love conquers all.
- [Tom] That is such a lie!
- 20 room house in Beverly
Hills, three full swimming pools,
- [Joel] You know, if you picked up
a few more shifts you could move there.
- I don't believe in any of that anymore.
- [Joel] Say hello to the folks, Susie.
- And I don't think that
you really do either.
- It's all going to
come true, it's got to.
The law of averages.
- [Joel] I'm average.
I'll make it.
- That law doesn't seem
to work for us, Johnny.
- Hey come here.
- [Tom] Ow, your implant inflated again.
(telephone ringing)
- I'll get it.
- [Joel] Saved by the bell.
- [Tom] Go ahead, answer
the phone, Montgomery Clift.
- [Joel] Oh, this must be
that guy from pomade calling.
- Hello?
Sidney, yeah?
Bernie!
- [Joel] How's Bridget?
- Hey, it's about time you gave me a call.
- [Crow] Fat brown suit,
eight bucks a week?
- The producer wants to meet me?
Tonight?
I'll be over like a guided missile.
- [Joel] Only bigger and dumber.
- Baby, this might be it.
- Who was it?
- Bernie my agent,
- [Crow] Bernstein?
Set up a meeting for me
tonight at 12 o'clock,
with a Broadway producer.
- [Tom] Show called, Moose Murders.
- That late at night?
- Honey, you know show business?
Why if a guy wants to meet me at midnight,
so I'll meet the guy at midnight.
Oh come on, how 'bout dinner, huh?
- [Joel] Ring baloney?
- You know the old saying, a
hungry actor never gets a job.
- [Crow] I've never heard that.
- [Joel] She's not buying it.
- [Crow] Last night it was Joe Papp,
then it was Herald Prince,
I'm sick of it, sick.
- Well, back to junior jumble.
Here I go.
- [Crow] Act with Rosemary.
(train on a track)
(door shutting)
- It came, it came, it came.
You guys, Joel,
open it up.
- [Joel] Hey Crow,
what is this?
- Well you see, four to six
weeks ago I ordered a series
of acting lessons on records
from the So You Want to Act,
Institute of Acting,
just like in the movie.
- Oh lucky, hey did you order those
from those Sally Struthers
commercials where she goes,
"Do you wanna make more money?
Sure we all do."
- No.
- It says, costarring
with Scott Baio, you.
Okay lets see here, we've got
scenes from Charles in Charge,
scenes from Happy Days,
we got scenes from Lansky's Beauties,
scenes from Who's Watchin' the Kids,
and scenes from Joanie Loves Chachi.
- Yes!
I decided against the deluxe
edition, which included scenes
from his movies, Zapped, Bugsy Malone,
of course you knew that, and
The Boy that Drank too Much.
I just didn't think I was ready, and
I thought it would give me
something to work towards.
Okay, it says here for
this scene, I'm Joanie.
- Hey Joanie.
- Hey Chachie.
Uhh, no, no, no, no.
That's not right, I'm sorry,
can we take it from the top everyone?
Please.
Thank you.
- [Tom] Hey Joanie.
- Hey Chachie.
Hey Chachie.
No, excuse me but, what
exactly is the subject here?
Is hey combative, or a derivative,
or just conversational?
- Well it sounds like an
affectionate acknowledgement to me.
- Well remember Crow, at this
point in Joanie and Chachie's
relationship they're newlyweds
and they have this entire
history together from
their years on Happy Days,
so there's also that dynamic.
And they're struggling with Chachie's
fledgling singing career.
- True, and Joanie is also
trying to cope with the fact
that all their female friends
see her husband, Chachie,
as a hunky heart throb.
- Precisely.
- Hey Chachie.
- Crow you got it.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- [Crow] Think so?
- Yeah, we'll be right back.
- Yeah, guys I'm gonna need a
big hug after rehearsal today.
- You are so tense.
(upbeat dance music)
- [Tom] Hey look, you know who that is?
- [Crow] No.
- [Tom] I'll give you a hint,
♫ I sing whenever I sing whenever I sing ♫
- [Crow] Oh no.
- [Tom] Yup.
- [Joel] Hey, the cops ate my chiclets.
Hey, how come I don't even know you,
and you keep bailing me out, what gives?
- [Crow] Hey Vern!
- [Joel] Ernest does
a nickel up in Attica.
- How'd you get into the act?
- [Joel] I replaced Gummo.
- [Tom] I'm your guardian angel.
- Mr. Tucker wants to see
you tonight after closing.
- [Crow] Strike the set.
- What for?
Doesn't he know that my
mother won't gimme a dime.
Unless I straighten up and
go live with her on that
lousy ranch her husband gave her.
- Mr. T. Just wants to make
you a business proposition.
- Me?
That's a laugh.
(fake laughter from audience)
- Mr. Tucker don't appreciate
laughing, so you just beat it.
- Hey Leland!
- [Joel] Love that shot!
(beatnik music)
Wait, what's his deal?
- [Crow] Oh, it's a woman.
You know guys, if this is
what being beat was all about
I'd rather be a shallow
post-boomer, like you.
- [Joel] Hey.
- [Crow] Oh, it's a Jules Feiffer cartoon.
(flute music)
- [Joel] Hey, it's Olive Oil.
- [Crow] Oh Popeye.
- [Joel] Maybe we shouldn't
have gotten rid of the T.V.?
Oh I get it, it's a Sadie Hawkins Dance.
- [Crow] There's a painting
of Marty Allen back there.
Hello there.
- [Joel] Yeah, I need liquor
to deal with this weird action.
- [Tom] Kinda like beatnik twister, huh?
- [Joel] Twisted Sister.
- [Crow] Forbidden dance of Laura Petrie.
- [Joel] The more I drink,
the more talented you become.
- [Tom] They remind me of Fred and Ginger.
- [Crow] Yeah, Fred
Travalena and Ginger Baker.
- [Tom] Zing!
- [Crow] Look at the pie on him.
- [Joel] Oh my God.
I told you kids, no
parties while I'm gone!
- [Crow] I've come to
look at the apartment.
- You're pretty far out I'd say.
- Far out and floating.
I just received the seventh
rejection, and I'm on one now.
- Congratulations.
- [Joel] No see that means it didn't sell.
It's a bad thing.
- You and me gotta make some conversation
where it's a little more quiet.
- [Joel] You know, all these people
are in middle management now.
- You know what they say about my book?
- [Crow] It sucked?
- They say it stinks.
- [Joel] Smell it, see if you agree.
- You know, the funny part
about it is that they're right.
- What do you care what they think?
- A year of my life went
into that stinkin' book.
- Writin' books is for eggheads.
- Mr. T's got a better idea.
- T?
Tucker.
- The same.
Sober up and be at the coffee
house after closing tonight.
- [Joel] My Three Sons go beat.
- There's no place else I got to go.
- [Crow] Don't get no better than this.
- [Joel] Theo Bikel?
This must be 200 Motels.
- [Tom] Wonder how I can
make my life more depressing?
Try this place.
- [Crow] It's the devil's workshop.
- [Tom] Hey, there he is.
- [Joel] A character
actor to see you, sir.
- Grab a chair, it's on the house.
- Thanks.
- You cats more or less acquainted?
- Yeah.
- Then we can start you off from scratch.
- [Crow] Can I start you
off with some appetizers?
- Too bad we ain't got no
floor show for you gents,
but once Mr. T goes into his
filibuster you ain't gonna
miss the dancin' girls at all.
- [Crow] Shut up.
- [Joel] Shut up.
- Not that we ever get much romantics
in these here surroundings.
- Sidney I don't dig you.
All this chopper music but no tune.
- You know what the trouble
with you beat guys is?
- [Joel] You're so '50s.
- Who's you in likeness?
- You don't talk English very good.
- Come on, Tucker didn't get us over here
to improve our speech.
- [Tom] Ernest Hemingway?
- Not your speech, gentlemen,
but perhaps your finances.
- [Tom] Pyramid Game?
- The man is talking about Brent?
- The man is talking about money.
- [Crow] Get your paws off
me you damn, dirty beat!
- You gentlemen have been
among my steadiest customers.
I've had the opportunity
of studying you closely.
- You're writing the great American novel?
- [Joel] No, I'm doing a
Northern Exposure spec script.
- Nor am I casting a play,
nor attempting to furnish
psychological guidance
to a poor little rich boy.
- Alright, alright.
You've told us what you're not doing,
now would you mind telling
us what you are doing?
- Not at all.
- [Joel] I'm reading
for Mel Brooks tomorrow.
- I'm preparing, with your cooperation,
to steal a million dollars.
- [Joel] Feel eleven.
- You say steal?
- Do you know anyone who's
giving away a million dollars?
- [Tom] Ed McMahon?
- Except Uncle Sam, of course.
- [Crow] I don't get it.
- You're talkin' about some sort of crime?
- What's in a name?
A writer of some ability once remarked,
"A rose by any other name,
would still have thornes."
- [Tom] I think you're misquoting.
- [Mr. T] Certainly, Karen?
- [Joel] Did you call me Karen?
- What I wanna know is, why'd you pick us?
I mean us three.
- [Crow] I Saw your audition tape.
- Because none of you are
beat, you're merely beaten.
You're not detached, you're unemployed.
You're not dispassionate,
you're afraid, scared.
- [Joel] Can I still get
an omelette or something?
- [Tom] She just put her brain in.
What do I look like, a waitress?
Oh wait, I am.
- In exchange for a
few days of your lives,
I'm offering each one of you $200,000.
- [Crow] Okay, three.
- Money enough for you
to forget you can't act.
- [Joel] Hey, you're
in this film, too, bud.
- Perhaps start reading good ones.
For you to cut lose from your
lovely and wandering mother,
so that you may go to
hell in your own way.
- [Joel] That's kind of a
back handed compliment, huh?
- [Crow] Thanks for those
quick character sketches, boss.
- My plan is based on
the interesting fact that
if you take a train from
Los Angeles to New York,
there's a four hour stop over in Chicago.
- [Joel] It's the SAT caber.
- What's so interesting about
Chicago?
- [Tom] My kind of town.
- Any town where you steal a
million dollars is interesting.
Before I go into details...
- [Crow] Let's have a song!
I wanna press upon you that
no one can change their mind.
No one.
- [Joel] Okay, you can.
Notice I didn't put that as a question,
for the simple reason that
I can buy any of your debts
for x dollars.
- [Tom] From Sharper Image.
- And x dollars can make
any of you x permanently.
- [Joel] And that's exactly what I mean.
- [Crow] Okay, who ordered the Special X?
- [Tom] I had the Dos X's.
- This isn't what I had in mind.
- I don't have a liquor license and
I don't believe in breaking small laws.
- [Tom] There are no small
laws, just small criminals.
- As per usual.
- Tomorrow you will get some
presentable clothes, and
perhaps a shave.
- [Joe] And a haircut two bits.
- You have plenty enough to travel.
Now the details of your exact duties,
our meeting place in Chicago and so forth,
you'll get from Sidney.
Your train tickets will be picked up here
tomorrow night at 8:30.
- [Crow] Okay, nine.
- Congratulations on
your association with me
on this magnificent undertaking.
- [Joel] Enjoy your sodas.
- It'll not only be financially rewarding,
but it might also bring us fame.
Anonymous of course.
Now for the details of the master plan.
- [Joel] First, you'll take
this Precious Moment's figure
and set it next to a clock
and an ashtray, then...
- [Tom] ♫ One less bell to
answer, one less egg to fry ♫
- [Crow] Honey, Kazan wants
me for On the Waterfront Two,
Electric Booblaloo.
- [Jeanne] Johnny?
- [Joel] Are you in another movie, dear?
- It's almost 4 o'clock.
- I know.
The producer was the windy type.
- [Tom] Kind of an actor vampire type,
can't see his ego in the mirror.
- Who is he?
- [Crow] Uhh, Joe, uhh David.
- Well, he probably has a name.
- Sal Houston
- [Joel] Big Jew from Texas.
- Never heard of him, Broadway?
- Really he's a show backer,
he has a civic of investors.
He said I was just right for the part.
- [Joel] The Jethro Bodine Story?
- Oh Johnny, you're not kidding!
- At 4 o' clock in the morning I'm not.
Why the devil can't a woman ever
learn a simple way of
squeezing a tube of toothpaste?
- Well then you did get it, huh?
(upbeat dance music)
- [Tom] Charles Foster
Kent and Martha Mitchell.
(yelling)
- [Joel] People try to put us down.
- [Crow] The Lockhorn's go slumming.
- You behave yourself, you
want them to accept you.
- Accept me?
That's not the idea.
Will I accept them?
- Bertha Luna.
- What's that?
Unmask, sir.
- Shh, that's King and
David, our poetry laureate.
- Oh I see, I guess he yodels, too.
- Oh Russ.
- Tourists.
- [Tom] Old one eye is back.
- From nothingness to nothingness.
- [Joel] He's reading the menu.
- [Tom] Nice one.
- That's us goin' a fools' errand
before they throw a butterfly net over us.
- [Crow] Hey man, that's beautiful.
- I've got my eye on you.
- [Tom] My hungry eye.
- And vice versa.
- And that includes your language.
- [Joel] Wait, it doesn't
say that in the script.
Where did that all come from?
- A sad train, are the five senses.
- [Crow] I always get
the skillet scramble.
- At least we won't have to
listen to that stuff anymore.
- I happen to like it.
- Well I like ole' Betsy better.
- That rifle make you
feel anymore like a man?
- Smell nostrils, hear old ears
- Bravo old majesty.
- Thank you, old squid.
- [Crow] Hey, that'd make a great term
for someone who's not very hip.
- [Joel] Yes it would.
- [Tom] Thank you, Mr. Cooper.
I think he's doin', Crap's Last Eight.
- A hat box, it has no content.
- [Crow] Much like this film.
- A brain is missing.
- It's been missing all night!
- [Joel] Do you mind if
we dance with your date?
- Gentlemen, gentlemen.
- [Joel] Could we get
our order to go, please.
- King, we enjoyed it.
Truly we did.
- [Crow] My husband's very hip at home.
- I am bugged.
- [Joel] God of Facial Hair!
(cheering and whistling)
- Irwin Corey, everyone.
Irwin Corey.
- I'm so sorry.
- [Tom] What're you tellin' me for,
I'm Lyle Waggoner, aren't I?
No, maybe not.
- Well, the noble thespian has arrived.
- [Joel] Hey, I'm as
hetero as the next guy.
- You got the tickets?
- No but they're here.
Tucker left 'em with Miss I.Q.
before her took off for
Chicago with Sidney.
- Well, what happened?
- She won't part with them
'til the stroke of 8:30.
She takes Tucker's word rather literally.
(audience making siren sounds)
- Did I see you adult--adulterating,
oh spiking that coke?
- [Joel] Cut!
It's medicine.
Four out of five New York
doctors recommend it.
- Oh really?
- [Crow] Wow, what a comeback.
- Yes?
- What about the tickets?
- You'll get them at 8:30.
- But it is 8:30.
- [Tom] Somewhere in the world.
- It is 8:10, precisely.
- Karen,
- [Joel] I'll have the
chicken wings.
- Yes, John?
- Where'd you get that pretty watch?
- Dear Sidney sold it to me,
and at a great personal loss.
- I'll bet.
- [Crow] Ow!
- Well, it's not working.
- Huh?
- [Tom] My wrist?
It still works, see?
(knocking)
Come in?
No wonder it's been 8:10 for three days.
- I'll never trust that
Sidney again, that H-E-A-L.
- [Tom] She's Danielle Quayle.
- Now would you mind
giving us the tickets?
It really is 8:30.
- [Joel] Can we have
the T-I-K-I-T-Z, please?
- Alright, but turn the other way.
- [Tom] Waitress, can we
order over here, please?
- [Crow] Hey, while you're in
there, can I have a newspaper?
- Here.
- [Joel] Oh thanks.
Hey, they're all warm and wet.
- [Crow] Can I have my check, no I mean,
can I bring you your check, yeah.
- Trust me, you'll have lots
of time for that, eventually.
- [Crow] Huh?
- [Joel] ♫ Driving along,
footloose and fancy free ♫
- [Tom] Thank you for not smoking.
- Mr. T,
- [Joel] Move over.
- I'm puzzled kind of.
- [Crow] If there was only one gunman...
- They're all creeps.
- Creeps?
- [Tom] You know, who committed
to reelect the President.
- I simply don't get it.
Here you form up a masterpiece, and then,
with all the expert pros
available and on tap,
you hire them creeps.
Rank amateurs.
- [Joel] I trust Howard Hunt, come on!
- The exactly the crux of my plan.
- [Tom] Don't say crux, please.
- I excite the sleeping
ambition of half talented men,
- [Crow] Thank you, sir.
- Giving each of them a
glimpse of the promise land,
the prospect of an hour of glory,
lift them our of the drab and
hopeless swamp of mediocrity.
- [Tom] You're hard to talk to, sir.
- Once they're inspired by
this last chance to excel,
the creeps, as you so poetically
put it
- [Crow] Thank you.
Will go on the mission with zeal
and a single purpose unmatched
by even the most expert
and practiced criminal.
- [Crow] So, Hardy's okay with you?
- That my good Sidney, is the
alpha and omega of my theory.
The beginning and the
end of my psychology of
directing the masterpiece of crime.
- [Crow] You know, Burger
King has a drive-thru.
(name drowned out by Crow's talking)
- Who's he?
- Another creep.
- [Crow] My boss, always coming
up with phrases like that.
- [Tom] Zing!
- [Joel] It's the Flying Nun.
- [Crow] It's Vertigo.
- [Joel] It's Roman Holiday,
and much, much more.
Now, after shopping we'll get some lunch,
then it's off to the Robert
Hall store to get some shoes.
- [Voiceover] Southern Pacific Sunset,
arriving on track four.
- [Joel] The remaining pizza
will go on sale for 15 cents.
- [Crow] Now let's see,
Rubber Fantasy, Latex World,
Butt Biters, and Newsweek, that'll do.
Here's somethin' for you.
- [Joel] Lee Harvey Oswald on vacation.
- [Voiceover] Union Pacific Challenger,
leaving on track five,
loading at gate number two.
- [Crow] Visit the off world colonies.
Whoops, just burped up a
little egg salad, whoops!
- [Tom] Nobody said
anything about a dome liner.
- [Crow] This seems
like the last scene from
The Untouchables.
Oh it's The Cotton Club.
- [Tom] No, it's Narrow Margin.
- [Joel] No, it's Murder
on the Orient Express.
- [Crow] No, Runaway Train,
Golan/Globus production.
- [Tom] Strangers on a Train!
- [Joel] No, it's The Cassandra Crossing.
- [Crow] Silver Streak.
- [Tom] Super Train.
- [Joel] Maybe it's Murder
on the Orient Express,
did somebody say, oh I did, I said that.
(upbeat dance music)
- Wow, you know that
Chicago's a real nice city.
- It's quintessentially American.
- Oh okay, yeah, well let's pretend.
How 'bout if we had a four
hour layover like the rebels
in today's experiment.
What would you guys do, Gypsy?
- I'd go to the Medford
Outlet Store and shop.
- Gypsy, I don't think they
have a Medford Outlet Store
in Chicago, but you could
go to Water Tower Place
and shop.
- Okay.
- Joel, the first thing I'd
do, this is Chicago after all,
I'd burst through the main door of the
Continental Bank Building,
wielding my Tommy Gun,
shouting instructions over the dead
of the terrified screams,
yes I would take hostages.
I would demand, and receive,
unbreaking media coverage
of my senseless mayhem.
Negotiations would drag on for
three hours before breaking
down, then I'd start tossing
out bodies at seven minute
intervals, whoop better
get back to the train, you?
- Oh, I'd probably head out to
King Richard's Renaissance
Festival out in Gurnee, Illinois.
Probably get a leather mug
or somethin' like that.
Well, you know, then I'd
head down to Wrigley Field
and hang out with the bleacher bums,
probably drink beer out of it
or somethin' cool like that.
- Well you'd wanna call ahead and
make sure the game's not sold out Joel.
Well anyway, here's my plan.
Joel, I'd be equipped with a
good pair of walking shoes,
starting at Union Station,
I'd head east on Van Buren
and across the river, perhaps viewing
one of the intricate
lift bridges in action.
My heart would race as I
approach the world famous loop,
named for the loop formed by
the elevated train, or the "L,"
as it circles the downtown area.
It would be Tuesday
so my admission is free
at the Art Institute,
my uncle's membership
card gets me into the
member's cafeteria where I would doddle
over a delicious fruit cocktail.
Then I'd stroll down Michigan Avenue,
doesn't cost a dime to gaze and wonder
at the elite shops of
the Magnificant Mile.
"Oh no thanks ma'am,
just window shoppin'."
The new Comiskey Park beckons
warmly from Halstad and 35th.
The outfield bleachers are a great value
and always exciting.
White Sox promise to be a force in the
American League West for years to come.
Finally, thank goodness for my student ID,
I'd finish up with the Art
Institute, the Shedd Aquarium,
Lincoln Park, and Evanston.
- Sure seems like a lot of walking.
- But remember, I have a
good pair of walking shoes.
Oh but look, we still have a little time!
Sir George Solti and the
Chicago Symphony Orchestra,
the definition of world
class musicianship.
(beeping)
- Oh we've got a movie, son!
- Whoa!
(grating)
(door opening)
- [Crow] The Science and
Industry Museum has this
caveman exhibit
- [Joel] Alright, alright,
- [Joel] Please.
- Hello, George.
- Introduce me and I won't tell your wife.
- [John] This is my wife.
- [Joel] No, I mean the
woman I saw you with, oops.
- [John] Jeanne, George Lelund.
- How do you do, Mrs. Mapes.
Going to Chicago?
- New York.
- [Tom] Oh, Miss Marple is on the case.
- Drinks are on me.
- No thanks.
I think I'll turn in.
Why don't you have one with Mr. Lelund.
- Alright baby, sleep tight.
- [Joel] And don't look in my stuff.
- [Tom] I'm gonna see if the
Three Stooges are doin' a routine.
- [Joel] The seat's warm.
- It's his wife.
- [Joel] Introduce me to this fellow,
and I won't tell your wife.
- What's the idea of bringing her?
- It was her idea.
- Does Tucker know you brought her?
- I don't blame you, if that was my wife
I'd bring her along, too.
- [Crow] Take it back!
- She won't get in the way.
- She better not.
- Mr. Lelund?
- [Crow] We'll be pullin'
in to Hooterville soon.
- [Tom] Alfred Hitchcock in drag.
- I'm a great fan of your mother's.
- [Joel] Thanks, Dad.
- I understand she's coming home.
- Well, you probably know
more about that then I do.
- Thank you Mr. Lelund.
- [Joel] Hi Al, nice dress.
- Evem with the booze I still
don't care for your company.
- [Joel] What did I say?
- What's wrong with him?
- [Crow] He's got an upset tummy.
Charmed, I'm sure.
- [Tom] Don't wait up for me, Emma.
(train honking)
- [Joel] We will return
to Von Ryan's Express.
- [Crow] Chicago, hog
butcher to the world.
(upbeat humming)
- [Crow] Let us out of here.
Let us out of here.
- [Joel] Maxim 99 should
be here by now, Laraby.
Laraby, oh.
- [Voiceover] Des Moines,
Burlignton, and Colorado Springs.
- [Crow] And Cucabunga.
- [Joel] I can't believe
we didn't have our ticket,
they really enforce that.
Peter, I can't wait to
see the Statue of Liberty.
- [Tom] It's Chicago, dear.
- [Joel] I see you
brought your ventriloque.
- Look honey, I've gotta see
about the play, meet me...
- [Tom] Oh, you have to go the bathroom.
- John, why can't I go with you?
- It's not a social meeting.
You might call it politics.
See this man can put
in a good word for me.
- [Joel] You're draggin' me down!
- You're not ashamed of me, are you?
- Of course not darling,
it's just that I feel a bit
self conscience making a
pitch with you listening in.
- [Joel] You're a boat anchor.
- But I'm your wife.
- [Tom] I'm glad you
brought that up honey,
technically you're my wife but...
- Be a good girl, huh?
Here, go to the Punk Room and
have yourself a good time.
- [Crow] Get some change and
play as many video games as you want.
- Sure, I'll have a ball.
- [Joel] Oh a dollar, thanks.
- [Tom] Why is she wearing a fishing hat?
- Sweetheart,
- [Crow] This is a
- good luck.
- [Crow] Silver certificate.
- [Joel] Criminy, this one.
Ah, Ed Jenifick, please.
Jenifick, Ed.
- [Tom] Phil, can I see you in my office?
Move it, Phil.
- [Crow] I still like ya.
- [Joel] Damn, I gave her my last buck.
- [Crow] Empire State
Building on Nutrisystem.
- [Tom] No, no, no Tribune Tower.
(scatting)
- [Joel] Jeez, the donuts
are cheap in this town, man.
- [Crow] Oh hey, you're
coat's in the door.
Hey!
Oh, they're draining
the blinker light fluid.
- [Tom] Hey, I'm not half bad.
- [Joel] What, is he getting ready
for the renaissance festival?
- [Crow] Here's where the den will be,
and my room.
- [Joel] So, how's this supposed
to get 'em a million dollars?
- [Crow] The hat squad.
- That milk oughta be
quite a shock Ray's flat.
- [Joel] Yeah, don't cry over this, okay?
- [Crow] Is this a roadrunner thing?
(Crow's talking drowns out movie audio)
- [Tom] The beginning or
the end of that spot, Ed?
- [Joel] So, just behind
this grassy knoll, boss?
- Okay.
- On time for the second, Mr. T.
Let's hope the car's also on time.
- [Joel] Super Dave!
- We must also hope the racetrack
is up to it's usual high standards.
- [Joel] Huh, can't hear ya.
- That's a very nice high standard.
- Take the car on up.
- [Joel] Boing.
- [Crow] Suddenly it's
From Russia with love.
- [Joel] A Day at the Track,
The Manchurian Candidate,
The Dead Zone, The Man Who Knew too Much,
The Sugarland Express, Foul Play
- [Crow] I'm gonna kill that
milk to impress Jody Foster.
- [Joel] Tonight's episode,
milk, it does a body dead.
Dirt Harry, The Parallax
View, Ironside, the pilot,
Suddenly
- [Tom] ♫ High on a hill
lived a lonely goatherd ♫
I love my job.
Never think I have to get
up to work in the morning,
know what I mean?
- [Crow] Oh, we don't have to see this!
Chief, that's sick.
Mrs. Webb you're backing up.
That's a one way, Mrs. Webb.
Don't pull out.
- [Tom] What are the chances?
Someone else spilled milk.
- [Joel] Gentlemen, spill your milk.
- [Crow] My boss, always
comin' up with nutty schemes.
- [Tom] Buckle up for murder.
- [Joel] Tommy Kirk, assassin.
(mysterious music)
Jeez, I wish I had my Carmex.
(mummbling)
Maybe I could get on that
Bizarre Show, with John Byner.
The Timex Marlin, still ticking.
(mysterious music)
- [Tom] So, they're waiting, then?
- [Joel] Alright, well wait then.
- [Tom] Someone's tuning a piano.
I'm Ed Bradley, and this is 60 Murders.
- [Joel] ♫ Somethin'
new is comin' to town,
♫ And George the milkman's
bringin' it down ♫
- [Crow] And now, a few
murders with Andy Rooney.
The getaway chase game,
♫ Getaway ♫
- [Tom] Getaway!
- [Crow] Oh, not a very good driver.
- [Joel] Thank God I had this helmet on.
- [Crow] I'm a mess.
Oh, that's right, I did that.
- [Joel] Shoulda worn a cup.
Must get to Benny Hill taping.
(door shuts)
- [Crow] You okay ma'am?
Uh, sir.
- [Tom] Yup, first thing
to do to a injured person,
move 'em.
(sirens)
- [Joel] I'm really in trouble now,
stay together Cheeks, stay together.
- [Crow] Hey, can I get a ride into town?
- What happened?
- Some dope ran me right off the road.
- [Joel] That was part of the plan.
- [Crow] Drawing their
guns at a traffic accident?
- You fellows sure came
along at the right time.
- [Joel] That's great, disrobe.
- I dunno where this guy came from,
but he looks pretty badly hurt to me.
- Try not to worry about him.
- Put your hands up.
- [Crow] And a new world record.
Whoa, it really got up there.
- [Joel] Oh man, they
rolled a Good Humor truck.
- Alright let's go, move!
- [Joel] We're gonna run it, too, huh?
Now I get it,
no wonder he had a helmet on.
- [Crow] You guys gonna
finish these sandwiches?
- [Joel] Now I left the house today with
a long rope, a medium
rope, and a short rope.
- [Tom] ♫ Oh it's a hap-hap-happy day ♫
(whistling)
Oh no, we robbed a diaper service.
- Lovely, lovely.
- Worked 'em like a clock.
A million buck clock.
- Let's move.
- [Crow] But I like where I'm livin'.
- [Joel] This is about the
time Superman would show up.
- [Tom] So, why don't they move
the car closer to the truck?
- A little assistance, gentlemen.
- [Joel] Whoops, I accidentally
tied up one of our gang.
- Can take three.
(sirens)
- [Crow] Is that us?
- That's it, lets move.
- [Joel] Can I ride in front, Boss?
- [Tom] I'm thirsty, who's thirsty?
I've gotta Mountain Dew,
Diet Coke, Mr. Pibb..
- [Crow] Hey, hand me my slurpee.
- [Joel] Hey, Wally, we need
some shocks on this thing.
Ridin' kinda low.
- [Crow] The Blue Ridge
Mountains of Chicago.
- [Joel] Hey look, they drove onto the
Timmy and Lasse set.
- [Tom] You shoulda gone before the heist.
- [Joel] What a rush, they
totally don't know where we are.
- [Crow] An Ed Asner costume.
- We're five minutes behind schedule,
I suggest beat it.
- [Tom] Alright,
♫ Happy Birthday to me,
♫ Happy Birthday to me ♫
I shouldn't have.
- [Crow] Ha, he's buildin' a lean to.
- [Tom] Mr. Goodbars?
- [Joel] Hey, I found
some roots and grubs.
We could survive here for weeks.
(dramatic orchestra music)
- All the guns go into the hole as well.
- [Crow] Fire in the hole, ah nevermind.
- [Joel] So where's this go?
- [Crow[ In The Hole.
Movie's not over yet and
their strikin' the set.
- [Tom] Okay, what about this?
- [Joel] That would go in the hole.
- [Tom] Okay.
- [Crow] Lets see, hole,
hole, garage sale, hole
hole, Salvation Army, hole
- [Tom] Where's the turtle wax?
- [Joel] In the hole!
- [Tom] Kettle drum?
- [Joel] In the hole.
- [Tom] Hole, right?
- [Joel] Yup.
- [Tom] That?
- [Joel] In the hole.
- That stays with me.
(dramatic orchestra music)
- [Crow] Oh yeah, it's so
easy to find cop appliques.
- [Tom] Where's that go?
- [Joel] In the hole.
- [Tom] Belt, pants, heck I'm
just gonna jump in the hole.
(laughing)
(staccato piano music)
- [Joel] Could you look under the hood,
there's some funny sound comin' out of it?
- [Tom] Tell Zappa to turn the music down,
Ruth Underwood wants her vibes back.
(staccato piano music)
- [Crow] Be sure to put
that shovel in the hole.
- [Joel] Alright, who wants gum?
- [Crow] I do, I do.
- [Tom] I do, I do.
- [Joel] In the hole.
- You have exactly 30 minutes to get back
to the train, gentlemen.
- [Joel] And have your tickets ready,
they're real strict about that.
(loud drumming music)
Hey, I was supposed to
get the front this time.
- [Tom] But I get carsick,
you don't want that.
(door shutting)
- [Crow] You idiot,
your coat is stuck in that door again.
- [Tom] We can't get it out of reverse!
- [Crow] I just don't understand
the rebel part of this movie.
- [Joel] Well, robbing a
bank was pretty rebellious.
- [Crow] Yeah.
- [Tom] I used up that
dollar three hours ago.
- [Crow] Hey, she got a new head torte.
- [Tom] Pardon me, boy, oh forget it.
- [Joel] It looks like
she bought a snare drum.
- What took you so long.
- I made it, didn't I?
Come on.
- [Crow] I said, have your tickets ready.
- Hey Lelund, I'm Jack
Simpson, Chicago Morning Star.
- Why don't you guys leave me alone?
- How 'bout your mother?
There's a rumor Count
Opheno gave her the heir.
- Get outta my way.
- Listen, buster.
- [Tom] I hate her.
- You know, you could use
a little more good will
from the press.
- [Joel] So anyway, I
bought this darling drum
and it's got the snare and everything,
I don't see why we couldn't...
- [Crow] Hey, it's Ralph!
She's takin' the Hooterville trolley, too.
(startled screaming)
- [Tom] The Exorcist.
- [Crow] Flat point.
- How was your meeting?
- [Crow] Profitable.
- Johnny?
- Oh, my meeting?
- [Joel] Why can't Johnny fight?
- It went fine.
- You don't sound very enthusiastic.
- It was not very exciting
meeting a play write.
- Oh, I thought it was
one of the money people?
- Well, he's a rich play write.
- Oh, what's his name?
- [Joel] Rich.
- What is this a cross examination?
- [Crow] Nobody expects
to cross examine...
(training bumping)
- [Joel] Oh, sorry.
(train whistle)
- I'm sorry, honey.
- [Joel] I'm a jerk, you know that!
- I guess my nerves are on edge a bit.
- [Crow] George Bernard
Shaw was teasing me.
- His name was Sal Houston.
- [Joel] Yeah, a big
Jew from Texas, whoops.
- That's the man you said
you met in Hollywood.
- [Tom] No, that was
the other Sal Houston.
The Chicago one.
- Yeah, that's right.
I meant to tell you, honey,
he flew in yesterday.
- [Joel] We'll never use
the closets in our house.
(upbeat dance music)
- Excuse me, Mr. Miller.
- [Joel] Love Tropic of
Cancer, just had to tell ya.
- [Crow] Hey, it's Merritt Stone.
- [Tom] No it isn't.
- [Crow] Yes it is.
- [Tom] It's not.
- You're a writer, eh?
- [Joel] I guess not.
- If I could just sit down
all the true-to-life things I've see.
- [Crow] You'd throw up.
- But you and me could.
You are a writer, aren't you?
- [Joel] Yeah, I write
about the life of the mind.
- You know, everybody I've
told about my memoir says,
- write a book.
- [Joel] Shut up.
- [Tom] Like, I once saw a
woman with an unusual hat.
- The same thing's happened to me.
- I wish I could type.
Say, here's my card.
50/50 on all my stories, alright?
- [Crow] Thank you,
Mr. Animal Rummy is it?
- Thanks Mr. Miller.
- I'll call you.
- Thanks a lot.
- [Joel] I'll bet he never called.
Now let's see, where was I?
A screaming comes across the sky.
- [Voiceover] As of this
hour, the police have no leads
as to the armored car robbery in Chicago.
- [Joel] Hey, turn it
up, this is my heist.
So, you gals are in a band?
We're Heart.
- Reverend, do you know
what I think is responsible
for all of this crime?
- [Crow] Eisenhower.
- I haven't the most
remote idea Sister Petchal.
- The people involved.
- [Tom] Our link letter,
they all have our link letter on 'em.
- Who is it?
- [Tom] Just a second.
Hold on I'm countin'
all the loot we stole.
Whoops, sorry I didn't say that.
- [Crow] Got the five bucks you owe me?
I wanna get some chips.
- [Joel] Art Linkletter.
- Isn't it?
- [Crow] Kinda cute?
- What're you doin' with a gun?
- Just keepin' it company.
- What's the matter with you?
Tucker warned us about guns.
- I need a gun to protect
my beautiful money.
- Your money?
- [Crow] It's for my student loans.
- [Joel] Think fast.
- There's your cut.
Now you get outta here.
- You don't think you're
gonna get away this?
- The only thing you can
do is yell for the cops,
but you won't do that, not
with your beautiful wife.
- [Tom] This is not my beautiful wife.
Yes I can certainly see where
you'd wanna keep that money.
I can certainly side with your
side of the argument here.
No doubt about it.
(crashing)
- [Crow] This is just like
Treasure of the Sierra Madre,
only it's not good.
(humming an upbeat, dramatic song)
(banging)
- [Joel] Now, to return
this to Marshall Fields.
- [Crow] Goodbye, nice workin' with ya.
(door opening and shutting)
- I don't see that Lelund boy anywhere.
- Probably drinkin' his dinner.
- Oh Hattie you know very well
it's not drinkin' that
got him into the papers.
- [Tom] Donuts?
- [Crow] Pst, come on.
It's about the heist.
- [Joel] My waist?
- [Crow] No, the heist.
- Reverend?
- [Joel] Blue Jeans.
(door opening)
(train bell ringing)
You bitch.
- What are you doing with that?
- I've just had a fight with George.
I had to slug him.
- [Crow] It was so freeing.
- Thieves falling out?
- He wanted to keep all
the money for himself.
- I don't want it here,
what about your compartment?
- And have Jeanne find it?
- I don't want it here.
- What do you suggest?
We call the conductor and
have him keep it for us?
- [Tom] You know I didn't mean that.
- You've gotta talk
some sense into George.
- [Joel] I can't stay mad at you.
Come on let's hug.
- [Crow] Mickey Mouse.
- [Joel] M-U-R-D-E-R
- [Tom] I see your point,
but if we do hide the loot in my room,
then the cops might find it
and then we're gonna be...
- [Crow] He's got a nice
round one, doesn't he?
- [Joel] It's Floyd Terbone, hmm.
- [Crow] Well, we're
rebels, here's our chance.
Disturb, disturb, disturb, disturb.
- [Tom] Is he bugging you?
- [Joel] No.
He's a mess.
- [Tom] Chocolate mess.
- [Crow] (sniffing) Steve, Steve!
- [Joel] Yuck, good
thing the carpet's brown.
- You forgot to mention one thing,
you put a bullet through his brain.
- All I did was hit 'em.
- [Joel] It was a bullet.
- I didn't use a gun.
This is the one I took from him.
Take a look for yourself.
- [Joel] Hmm, kids, shot this guy for you.
Ham in fridge, Mom.
- Suicide.
- Except that looks type written.
And I got gun.
- [Crow] I got gun.
- You know who's typewriter
that was written on?
Mine!
The "e" on my typewriter prints lower
than the rest of the letters.
- [Crow] Wow!
- Let's get out of here.
- No.
- [Joel] No?
They could trace that note to me.
- He's tried committing suicide before.
- [Tom] Did it work?
- You could get rid of your typewriter.
- That would mean that only you and I know
that it was murder.
- I think you're forgetting someone else.
- [Crow] God knows, Davey.
- Who?
- The murderer.
(laughing)
- [Joel] Oh no, it's a social gospel.
- I quite agree with you Sister Ventura.
Mine too is a small town.
Yet somehow, in such
Arcadian surroundings,
sin doesn't seem to be quite so sinful.
- How true, how true.
- [Tom] Travelling with
Gertrude and Alice.
- [Crow] Yeah, but I still
say if we hid the loot
with the body that'd be killing
two birds with one stone.
- Those two men look as though
they've just seen a ghost.
- How many men are afraid of ghosts
who are not afraid of the all high?
- You put that very beautifully, Reverend.
- [Joel] But shut up.
- Thank you.
(door slamming)
Oh my knee, oh jeez.
- [Tom] Oh, that's better.
- I think I better get back to Jeanne
before she starts worrying.
- I'll get rid of the typewriter.
- [Crow] Where's my kiss?
What about my kiss?
- [Joel] I still suck,
I thought I had written
something good for a second,
I don't know why.
Gordon Lish is gonna give me
a really bad grade for this.
- [Tom] ♫ Summer breeze,
makes me feel fine,
♫ Goin' through the jasmine ♫
As a gift to the reading public,
he's throwing his typewriter away.
Thank you.
- [Crow] He thinks he's Harry Truman.
- [Tom] I'll just drop these in the mail.
- [Joel] Ow!
- [Tom] Sorry!
- [Joel] Man, I wish Bret Easton Ellis
would do that with his typewriter.
- [Tom] Yeah.
- [Crow] Yup.
- [Tom] So, do I come here often?
- Very clever Mr. Miller.
A wise precaution on your part.
- Who are you?
- I'm the Reverend Basal Cunningham,
or should I say the very Reverend.
- You're Tucker!
- [Crow] We just did a
heist together, remember?
- I'm the Reverend Basal Cunningham
of Penbrook, New Hampshire.
- [Tom] I believe, you
believe, that's who you are.
- I should have known
you'd never let that money
get too far away from you.
You're the one who killed George!
- One less share to disperse.
- [Tom] One less spell to ask.
- And now Mr. Miller
- [Crow] I'm gonna shave your mustache.
- There'll be still another share less.
- [Crow] Cross and a switchblade.
- You don't have to kill me.
- [Crow] Murder on the Dis-Orient Express.
- I don't want any of your damn money!
(train horn)
- [Crow] So hey, what happened?
I don't get it.
- Conductor!
- [Crow] I'm lonely.
- Are we on time?
- Why yes we are.
- We hate to be late.
- So do we.
Now if you'll excuse me
I have some work to do.
- I think lateness is a defect
in a person's character.
- This train is never late, goodnight.
- [Joel] Gary Busey after the accident.
- [Crow] Bookends.
- He's a disgrace to the uniform.
- [Crow] I love a disgrace to an uniform.
- The air conditioning on
this train is splendid,
but there's nothing like
God's own air to breathe.
- Well maybe so, Reverend,
- [Crow] So out you go.
But it's against regulations.
- Regulations against breathing?
- You all have your little
joke, do you Reverend?
- [Tom] You make me sick.
- [Joel] Why don't we go?
- Goodnight, Reverend.
- Goodnight to you, sir.
- [Crow] What a dope.
(train engine)
(doors closing)
- Joel, we got our short stories ready.
I'm so excited.
Having a writer's
workshop was a great idea.
I may even give up
writing spec scripts and
concentrate solely on fiction from now on.
- Oh that's great Crow.
It's open up a whole new area
of writing for you to fail in.
- That's not very supportive, Tom.
- [Joel] Thank you.
- Yeah, whatever.
Joel, what made you decide to have this
dumb ole' writer's workshop anyway?
- Well it's from this new
creative writing book I got
Called, Writing Down the
Tracks, by Merritt Stone,
the conductor in today's experiment.
- He's not Merritt Stone.
- Whatever, let's here
your stories you guys.
- Okay, me first, me first.
The vast emptiness of space lay before me.
The star and the galaxies
were apart from me,
yet seemed inside me also.
All of my deepest yearnings,
my most profound inner most thoughts,
my striving, aching sole that
longed to love and be loved,
all of these things were reflected
in the twinkling of the stars,
the rising of the moon as I venture...
- Uh, Crow listen, that's
all very well and good
but if Merritt Stone were here...
- [Tom] He's not Merritt Stone.
- If Merritt Stone were
here he would wonder why
there's no scene where
a ticket get punched,
and no one has said, "Can
I take your bags, please?"
As far as I can tell,
your story doesn't even involve a train,
I'm sorry Crow, this is gonna
need extensive re-writes
if you wanna please Merritt Stone.
Tom?
- He's not Merritt Stone, thank you.
A stately, plump Buck Mulligan
came down from the stairwell
and laid a razor on the...
- Hey, you stole that from Joyce Dewitt.
- Crow, it's James Joyce and
whether he stole it, or not,
his story has no sense of place.
We have no idea if it takes
place in Massapequa Park,
Amityville, Copage Lindenhurst, Babylon
♫ Change a Jamaica for a ♫
- [Crow] That doesn't, ugh.
- That doesn't, ahhh.
- Can I read my story?
- Sure Gypsy, go ahead.
- A train leaves a
station at two p.m. going
90 miles an hour.
Another train leaves another station
going the opposite
direction at five p.m. going
60 miles an hour.
How long before they meet?
- Oh Gypsy, that is everything
great literature should be,
according to Merritt Stone.
- [Tom] He's not Merritt Stone!
(upbeat dance music)
(all characters are
arguing at the same time)
- We could be witnesses.
- Ladies, please.
- [Crow] Ladies, back me up on this.
- [Joel] Merritt Stone,
ladies and gentlemen.
- [Tom] He's not Merritt Stone.
- You should have kept the door shut.
- How'd I know they gonna
be wondering around?
- Well see that no one else comes in.
- Yes sir.
- [Joel] I just told you
not to open the door.
- Shocking, utterly shocking.
- Well he tried it before,
this time he made it.
- Tried what before?
- Suicide.
- [Tom] Did it work?
- [Crow] Old pastrami, canned kraut,
six bagels bring home for Emma.
- What makes you
think it was suicide?
- [Joel] Sit on the evidence,
why don't ya?
- Well, what else would it be?
Murder?
- [Joel] Well, that's an option.
- Why do you say that?
- This note is type written.
- Well?
- Where's the typewriter?
- How well did ya know him, Johnny?
- Who?
- The Lelund boy.
- [Crow] Well, we dated.
- Casually, why?
- This has been a funny trip.
- [Tom] Yeah, sure in
a dream of Gallagher.
- Well I haven't been splitting my sides.
- I didn't mean it that way.
- What are you doin'?
- What, I'm getting a cigarette.
- [Joel] Hey don't take my last cigarette.
- Johnny!
Where'd you get all that money?
- Stage money.
- [Crow] You're in Guys and Dolls?
Bill never carries stage money at home.
- [Joel] Well, it's gonna take me
a few minutes to rationalize this one.
(train whistling)
- [Joel] Ladies and
gentlemen, Merritt Stone.
- [Tom] He's not Merritt Stone.
- I wired ahead to the police.
They'll meet the train
in Newark in the morning.
- Sound idea.
- [Joel] Father Dowling Mysteries.
- One more thing,
- [Crow] You know, I've
always wanted to be a priest,
I've forgiven a lot of
people in the years...
- One of the passengers is missing.
- Indeed?
Who?
- That rider in compartment D.
Fellow I gave all my stories to.
- [Joel] You know, the guy you pushed off.
- He must have had a very
urgent reason to jump
from a speeding train, don't you think?
- A very good reason.
- Which was?
- His typewriter.
- [Tom] Oh hey, Edie Sedgwick.
(dramatic mysterious music)
- [Crow] And then, when I
was 19 my skin cleared up
and that was a good day.
- Jeanne
- Yes?
- [Joel] Is it almost my turn to sleep?
- About that money...
- What about it, Johnny?
- [Joel] Well I got it selling grit.
- I've been lying to you.
- [Crow] I'm not really
a submarine captain.
- Where did you get it?
- [Joel] Caddying.
- From the Chicago robbery.
- [Crow] The hydraulic wife.
- What are you saying?
- I helped steal it.
- [Crow] You got a job?
I love the Chicago robbery.
- Oh Johnny, no!
- It seemed to be the
answer to everything.
I wanted to give you everything.
- [Crow] Well not everything,
we don't have the closet space,
but you know what I mean.
- [Jeanne] Johnny.
- Jeanne, George Lelund
didn't commit suicide.
I mighta had the guts to
go through with the robbery
but I can't take murder.
- Murder?
- [Joel] Well I guess
this puts my card game
on Wednesday night in perspective.
- [Tom] I love it when
my plans come together.
Next week, on The Rebel Set.
(train engine)
- [Crow] Oh, a love scene.
- [Joel] No.
- [Tom] No tunnel.
- [Joel] Hey!
- [Tom] ♫ Newark, Newark ♫
- [Crow] I'm a cop, I commute.
- [Joel] I work the day watch on the
722 Long Island railroad,
my name's Reading.
- Wait here.
- Keep all the other cars closed.
- [Crow] I like your uniform.
- [Joel] Oh, this'll be fun.
- Police are coming aboard.
- [Joel] They're coming
to take me away, ha ha.
- I'm going with you.
- I'd rather you didn't.
- [Crow] They don't have connubial cells.
- I love you, Jeanne.
- [Crow] It's Cynthia.
- I know you do and I'm
going with you, Johnny.
All the way.
- [Joel] Thanks for being so supportive
of my acting career that
I took to a life of crime.
- Where's the body?
- [Crow] Follow your nose.
- [Tom] Hey, it's a picnic casket.
- [Crow] Maybe they think
they're pickin' up Moses.
- [Tom] Maybe it's more of a
light summer casket, I'd say.
- [Joel] Okay, who wants
his Visa card here?
- [Joel] I have no face.
It's Officer Not Appearing in this Scene.
- You wait here.
My name's John Mapes.
I've got something to tell the police.
- Let him in, Pat.
- [Crow] Yeah, let's
have a few more people
to kick around the crime scene.
- George Lelund didn't commit suicide.
- [Joel] I did.
- We know that.
- You tryin' to confess to his murder?
- No sir, but the both of us were involved
in the Chicago armored car robbery.
- [Tom] I'm not interested,
try the next car.
- Are you having delusions of grandeur?
- I know where the money is.
- [Joel] There's money in direct sales.
- Why this sudden urge
to tell all, Mr. Mapes?
- Well, because I've been a fool.
(Crow makes a squishing sound)
- [Crow] Whoops, that
was even more foolish.
- Alright, show me.
- [Joel] And still I have no face.
- Your wife?
- Yes sir.
- [Crow] Sorry.
- [Joel] Hey.
- Newark, I'd know it anywhere.
- [Joel] Even if I wasn't in Newark,
I'd know I was in Newark.
(train horn)
(thudding)
- [Joel] That wasn't
part of my master plan,
but it was just for fun, you know?
Gotta like that.
- And thus did mighty Samson
overcome the Phillistine.
- [Crow] By hitting him
overhead with a sitting stick
and wearing a priest costume?
I didn't know that.
(door shutting)
- Here's your money.
- [Tom] I hid it with my negligee.
- [Crow] Uh, could I
take back the confession?
I seem to have, uh...
- Who do you think
you're kidding?
- But that's where we hid the money.
- Yeah, where did you hide the killer?
- Tucker!
There's your killer!
- Open up Mapes, open this door.
- [Joel] Okay honey, you go
here, and this will go there.
(glass shattering)
- [Crow] Plenty of room now.
Oh my hands, ow!
(dramatic music)
Please ma'am, I'm just tryin' to
maul down your husband in cold blood.
Step back.
(crying)
- [Tom] Oh my arches.
(Jeanniecrying)
- Alright, sister.
- [Joel] Fine, I won't kill
your husband, what a baby.
(dramatic music)
- [Crow] Lets see, I
put a penny on the track
right about here.
- [Tom] Officer, were you lookin' for me?
- [Crow] Hey a penny.
- Come on.
- [Joel] Everybody's doin' it.
(upbeat dance music)
- [Tom] ♫ A mighty fortress is our God,
♫ A bulwark never failing,
♫ Our Helper He, amid the flood,
♫ Of mortal ills... ♫
- [Crow] It's John Candy!
- [Tom] Hey, that was John Candy.
♫ A mighty fortress is our God, hey ♫
(scatting)
- [Joel] Richard Kimble.
- [Crow] Some of us are goin'
to lunch, you wanna come?
(Tom howling)
Well, where do you wanna eat?
- [Joel] Where there's a
really nice muffin shop,
there it is.
(train engine)
Hey, Wisconsin's the other way.
(dramatic chase music)
(gun shots firing)
- [Tom] ♫ It only takes a spark,
♫ To get a fire going ♫
- [Crow] Well maybe Thomas the Tank Engine
will come to save the day.
- [Tom] From Hollywood,
The Tonight Show starring
Johnny Carson.
- [Crow] Father, hold up,
there's some stuff I wanna confess.
- [Tom] Okay Father, I
took some lion's nets, and
I read Lolita and I liked it.
Please forgive me, okay?
♫ So low, can't get under it,
♫ So high, can't get over it,
♫ So wide, can't get around it ♫
- [Crow] Father, Father
I had impure thoughts
three times last week,
about you.
(dramatic chase music)
And I have these doubts, you see?
And sometimes I get angry at people.
- [Joel] You have the right
to remain, ah forget it!
- [Crow] With Johnny's guests...
- [Joel] Beatniks, ladies
and gentlemen, beatniks.
Hello.
- [Crow] Hello.
- [Tom] Hello.
Hello.
- [Crow] We should really
get out the calisthenics.
- [Joel] That's funny,
thanks quirky threesome.
- [Tom] ♫ Oh sons of
God, gather around the ♫
- [Joel] Now look Father,
you gotta forgive me, see?
(train whistle)
- [Crow] E nomine patri.
- [Joel] Whoa, he can't take it there.
- [Crow] Go in Peace, say
no more, I'm outta here.
I feel better, I'm gonna
confess to him more often.
- [Tom] Light penance.
(crashing)
- [Joel] Priest on a hot tin roof.
- [Crow] Father Mannix.
- [Joel] Amen.
- [Tom] ♫ It sings my
soul, my savior got three ♫
- [Crow] Father Mannix, wait!
- [Joel] Amen.
I said you're forgiven,
now leave me alone.
- [Crow] Now I need some
advice on my marriage.
You're the only one I can
go to with these problems.
(thudding)
- [Joel] The heist has ended, go in peace.
- [Crow] Now there's something
you don't see everyday, Chauncey.
- [Joel] What's that, Edgar?
- [Crow] Priest beating the
hell out of a guy in a factory.
(banging and crashing)
- [Joel] Can I use your bathroom?
Thanks,
I'm with him!
Stay together cheeks,
stay together cheeks.
(gears grinding)
- [Crow] He's gotta return
that costume by noon.
- [Tom] I've had dreams like this.
- [Crow] He's nude!
- [Tom] I'm really steamed at you.
- [Crow] Nude man.
Okay look, you're fired from the caper.
- [Joel] Alright you two,
Marquis of Queensberry rules,
come on.
- [Tom] Who's the man in the white suite?
(dramatic chase music)
- [Joel] Look, there's a guy we can shoot!
Now he's beating up a milkman.
He hates people in uniform.
(scatting)
- [Crow] He's hitting him
with vermicelli, that's cruel.
Merry Christmas, have some tinsel.
- [Tom] For a big guy,
he's a lousy fighter.
He gets beat up by an elderly priest.
- [Joel] Yeah, he'd lose
a fight with Irene Ryan.
- [Crow] I am in a state
of grace, leave me alone.
- [Tom] Gangs of chain wielding
priests, next on Geraldo.
- [Joel] Hey, weren't you just nude?
- [Crow] Priest be nimble, priest be quick
Me too!
- [Joel] At the wine cellars
of Ernest and Julio Gallo.
(banging)
Bless you!
- [Crow] Now he's the Statue of Liberty.
- [Joel] He's a friar.
- [Tom] Forgive me Father,
for I have murdered.
- [Joel] That is the biggest
sub sandwich I have ever seen.
Look his coat is caught
in the door, again.
- [Crow] Nice basket, Phil.
- [Joel] I love that one.
- [Crow] Hi, what's your name?
I'm too ashamed to ask her for her ticket.
- [Tom] Tickets please, tickets.
(romantic orchestra music)
- [Joel] Hi honey, I'm home, kind of.
He's adorable.
- [Crow] Well, he helped pad out the film,
so he might get off.
- Oh Darling, what happened?
- Your husband helped nab a killer.
That'll be in his favor.
Come on fellow.
- [Tom] So, it'll only
be 20 or 30 years, honey,
so let's just say, I'd
take a lover if I were you.
- [Joel] Can I have the
checkbook or something?
The keys?
- [Crow] I've never been
to Joliet, what's it like?
(Crow's talking drowns out the beginning)
- Ms. Lelund.
- What difference does it make?
Poor little me, I'm not news.
- Now just try telling that to my editor.
- Well, really it's because
of my darling, darling boy.
I've come home to be a real mother to him.
- [Joel] Yeah, that's fine,
can I take you lunch rider now.
- I must confess, I've
neglected him, but now,
now the curtain rises
on a bright new horizon.
A new, and lovely life,
just the two of us.
I realize that above all
things, I'm a mother.
- [Crow] Check that.
- And you may quote me on that.
- Well thank you Ms. Lelund.
- [Joel] What a dark
comment on our society.
- [Crow] We've secretly taken herlive son,
and replaced him with this dead one.
Let's watch.
- [Joel] See what coffee houses can do?
- [Tom] So, all this happened because
Johnny got lost at the fair?
- [Joel] Well I guess I'll
have to give this hat back
to Colonel Blake now.
- [Crow] Cream chip
beef, that sounds good.
I wonder if I have any toast in the house.
- [Joel] The sad side of beatniks,
beyond the bangles and
the goatees lies pain.
- [Crow] Edward Platt will
be back in Shah in Africa.
(melancholy music)
(train engine)
(doors closing)
- Hey, Joel, why hasn't that
conductor guy, Merritt Stone,
been in more movies?
He's pretty good.
- Yeah.
- Aha, so I see you two
have fallen into it.
- Yeah, right.
Why are you dressed like Rawley
Fingers at a Playboy party?
- What do you mean by...
- Crow, I'm not sure, but I
think he's playing the role of
Hercule Poirot, the great detective.
- That is right, Joel.
I suppose you are all wondering why
don't you ever
- [Crow] Why I have gathered
step on my line again, please.
- [Crow] you here.
I am here to solve the
great Merritt Stone mystery.
- That's great, Tom, but we've
got a letter here to read.
It comes from a
Pat Braun
- [Tom] Come on guys, please.
Okay, Tom, what is the
great Merritt Stone mystery?
- Thank you, Joel.
Now if you will grab the
visual aid I have prepared
and follow along with me, please.
- Okay, got it.
- And no one is to leave the room.
Now then, we all agree that
the Gary Busey-like conductor
from The Rebel Set is
Merritt Stone, right?
- [Joel] Right.
- Wrong!
How could you be so stupid?
You make me puke.
- Jeez, calm down, it's
just Merritt Stone, Tom.
- And what was it that
led you big dogs to the
conclusion that it was Merritt Stone?
Gypsy!
(Screaming)
- 'Cause he was in Earth vs.
Spider and The Tormented.
- Wrong!
(screaming)
I too almost fell for that foolish trap.
Joel, Merritt Stone's name
appears in the credits to
Earth Vs. Spider, The
Magic Sword, and Tormented.
Put them on the board, please.
- Okay, got it.
- Thank you.
But, Gary Busey conductor
guy physically appears in
Earth VS Spider, Rebel Set, Giant Leaches,
and The Tormented.
Something was wrong, they didn't match.
I put my grey matter
together and I realized that
Jack Causlin appears in
The Magic Sword and the
Earth VS the Spider.
- You have a lot of free time, don't you?
- Quiet fool!
Was it possible that Jack Causlin
is actually Merritt Stone,
and vice versa?
- Yes.
- No!
- Ah, no!
- Yes!
His name did not appear in The
Rebel Set, The Giant Leaches,
or The Tormented, I was
back at the beginning.
Then a major break in the
case, Gene Roth's name appears
in the credits of Earth
VS Spider, The Rebel Set,
Giant Leaches, and Tormented.
I had my man.
Gentlemen, I put it to you
that Gene Roth is actually
Merritt Stone.
- I'm so relieved.
- I plan to celebrate with a
bottle of chateau marmot 52
and perhaps a bit of brie
- Hey, hey, wait up here.
If Gene Roth is Merritt
Stone and Merritt Stone is
in The Magic Sword with Jack Causlin,
could Jack Causlin
actually be Merritt Stone
and transitively Jack
Causlin could be Gene Roth.
- No, no, no you silly man
because we have a visual idea of
- But you don't have a
visual idea of Jack Causlin.
- Not as such, but...
- Well then, Jack Causlin
could be Merritt Stone.
- And if Jack Causlin
is Merritt Stone, and
Merritt Stone is in
Tormented with Gene Roth
then who is Jack Causlin,
and couldn't Jack Caulin be Gene Roth?
(sparking)
- We gotta stop doin'
that to that poor kid.
What do you think, sirs?
- Gene Roth?
Gene Roth was in She
Demons, a 1958 film with
Irish McCallahan but Jack Causlin,
Jack Causlin wasn't in She Demons,
so who's Merritt Stone?
Dear God, who's Merritt Stone?
- I'll get you for this, Joel.
- [Frank] Who is Merritt Stone!
(slow melancholy music)
- I am bugged.